LYNN RICHARDS

lynn@lynnrichards.net

778.987.0378

Vancouver BC, Canada

in linkedin.com/in/lynnrichards1

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Web developer with extensive experience in designing, developing, testing, and deploying applications. Demonstrated ability in leading software development projects, performing database management, and customer support. Able to effectively self-manage during independent projects, as well as collaborate in a team setting.

EDUCATION

CareerFoundry

Vancouver, BC

Full Stack Developer Certification

Cornell University

Ithaca, NY

Master of Engineering: Computer Science

The American University

Washington, D.C.

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- MS SQL Server, MongoDB
- CSS, JavaScript, jQuery
- Node, REACT, Bootstrap
- MS Office, Adobe Suite
- Git, Trello, Teamwork, Zendesk, and more...

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Fluent in English, French and Arabic.
- US Citizen with Canadian Permanent Residency.
- Avid cyclist, with top podium finishes at various races in B.C and AZ.

WORK HISTORY

IT Consultant - NGN Productions

Vancouver, BC • 09/2017-12/2022

- Used Google Apps Script (GAS) to automate a film repository which allowed producers to update and filter worldwide movie releases and generate automatic weekly reports for company executives.
- Managed customer support, website maintenance and the company's cast & crew database.

Project manager - Cycling Components Network

Vancouver, BC • 11/2015 - 05/2017

- Led a team of engineers through of all phases of the software development lifecycle to create cutting-edge online registration systems for clients such as *USA Cycling* and *Triathlon Canada*.
- Maintained project schedules, work breakdown structures, issue logs, and status reports ensuring timely completion of deliverables.
- Gathered, analyzed, and presented statistical membership reports for Triathlon
 Canada and The Vancouver Sun Run by writing an application that generated and
 compiled historical customers' membership data.

Web Developer - Self

Phoenix, AZ • 09/2009 - 11/2015

 Maintained client-server solutions for *The Cawley Company*, a worldwide provider for badge identification systems. Applications included an encrypted databasedriven badge ordering system for all *Carlson Hotel* branches, and online employee badge ordering systems for *Cintas*, and *Budget* offices nationwide.

Corporate Quality Senior Software Engineer - Intel Corporation

Chandler, AZ • 10/1995 - 09/2006

- Responsible for the design and development of the central repository for Intel's Customer Operational Shared Resource (COSR). Contributed to each step of COSR's n-tier application development lifecycle: design, development, deployment & support.
- Product owner of Intel's Change Management Information System: a client-server application that automates the notification of product changes to Intel's customer base worldwide. Contributed to the design, development, testing & support of the application.